A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Natural Resources, 2002-2014 (bulk 2009-2013)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Natural Resources, 2002-2014 (bulk 2009-2013)
The Library of Virginia
51125
16.5 cu.ft. (47 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Natural Resources
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 8 January 2014 by the Office of the Secretary of Natural Resources, 1111 East Broad Street, 4th Floor, Richmond, Virginia, 23219.
Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governor's top management team. The Office of Secretary of Commerce and Resources was created on April 8, 1972. The Secretary of Commerce and Resources was responsible for assisting the Governor in implementing policies for the conservation and use of natural resources, for promoting economic development, providing managerial guidance and direction to Commerce and Resources agencies, and developing and promoting Commerce and Resources programs and budgets. In 1984 the Secretariat was split into two separate offices, the Secretary of Economic Development and the Secretary of Natural Resources.
The Secretary of Natural Resources is a member of the Governor's Cabinet, and is appointed by the governor, and is subject to confirmation by the General Assembly. The Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for the direction of, or had jurisdiction over, the following state agencies and boards: Department of Conservation and Recreation, Department of Environmental Quality, Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, Department of Historic Resources, Marine Resources Commission, Museum of Natural History, and the Virginia Council on Indians. The Secretary of Natural Resources also served as the chairman of the Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, and was a Board Member of the Chesapeake Bay Commission. Additionally, the Secretary of Natural Resources was responsible for many smaller boards and commissions related to water control, pollution, rivers, waste management, and other environmental and recreational issues.
Douglas W. Domenech was appointed Secretary of Natural Resources in January 2010 and served for the entire administration of Governor Robert F. McDonnell. Maureen Matson served as Deputy Secretary of Natural Resources; Sara Benghauser served as Assistant Secretary of Natural Resources; and Anthony Moore served as Deputy Secretary for Chesapeake Bay Restoration.
Scope and Content
Records, 2002-2014 (bulk 2009-2013), created and maintained by Secretary of Natural Resources, Douglas W. Domenech, during the administration of Governor Robert F. McDonnell (2010-2014). The records include agendas, correspondence, decision briefs, memorandum, presentations, programs, reports, studies, and other working papers. There is correspondence and subject files that relate to Secretary Domenech, the state agencies that he oversees, environmental organizations that operate in Virginia, and projects initiated by Governor McDonnell. Legislative files contain material related to bills that were either under the purview of the Secretary of Natural Resources or upon which the Secretary wished to comment.
Wherever possible, the original order of the files has been maintained.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and Supporting Documentation, 2002-2014
Series II: Decision Memoranda and Briefs, 2010-2013
Series III: Legislative Files, 2007-2013
Series IV: Public Relations, Activities, and Visits, 2010-2013.
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and Supporting Documentation, 2002-2014 (bulk 2009-2013)., Extent: 18 boxes (6.2 cu. ft.) (Box 1-18)
  Series I: Correspondence and Supporting Documentation, 2002-2014 (bulk 2009-2013), is housed in eighteen boxes and arranged alphabetically by folder title. Included is correspondence, manuals, minutes, memorandum, publications, reports, studies, surveys, and other related materials. Of note are the files related to the restoration of the Chesapeake Bay including board meeting minutes, correspondence, memorandum, publications, reports, and strategic plans for Phase I and Phase II of the Chesapeake Bay Watershed Implementation Plan. Also of note are the files on the FMFADA (Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority). The 2005 BRAC (Base Realignment and Closure Commission) closed the military facilities on Fort Monroe and the FMFADA was created to establish a Reuse Plan for Fort Monroe when it was reverted to the Commonwealth of Virginia. The files include agreements, correspondence, environmental impact studies, manuals, meeting minutes, memorandum, reports, and other sundry materials.
  Included are files regarding the Chickahominy Indian Tribe and the Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2009 (S. 1178). Also included is a file regarding the establishment of The Hand Site historical highway marker for the Cheroenhaka (Nottoway) Indians of Southampton County, Virginia. Other files include federal projects such as energy efficiency and offshore wind; land and easement acquisitions by the Dept. of Conservation and Recreation; Governor's Commission on Economic Development and Job Creation; uranium mining; Smith Mountain Lake shoreline management; oyster management; and invasive species, among others.
  - Appalachian Trail Conservancy, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission, Annual report, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chesapeake Bay Protection and Restoration, Executive Order 13508, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Action Plan, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Governance and Goals, 2009-2013 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2010 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2010 September 9-10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2010 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2010 November 4-5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2011 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2011 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2011 May 5-6 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2011 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2011 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2011 September 8-9 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2011 November 9-10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2012 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2012 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2012 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2012 November 8-9 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2013 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2013 September 19-20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2013 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2013 November 14-15 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2013 November 15 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2013 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Meeting, 2014 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission, Reports, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chesapeake Bay Foundation, State of the Bay, 2010-2012 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chickahominy Indian Tribe, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Civil War Sesquicentennial, 2010-2013 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2009-2010 April (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2010 May-June (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2010 July-September (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2010 October-November (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2010 December (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2010, Misc. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2011 January (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2011 February-March (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2011 April-June (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2011 July-September (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2011 October-December (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2011, Misc. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2012 January-June (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2012 July-December (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, From Agencies Under OSNR, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, From Agencies Under OSNR, 2009-2011 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, From Agencies Under OSNR, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, From Agencies Under OSNR, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, From Agencies Under OSNR, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, VIP, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, VIP, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Cross Country Home Services, Presentation, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Department of Conservation and Recreation, 2009-2011 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, Budget, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, Position requests and approvals, 2010-2013 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, Report on Audit, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, Senate Bill 880, Report of the Working Group, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, State Assessment and Strategic Plan, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, Dangerous Wild Animals Report, 2012-2013 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Dept. of General Services, Public-Private Education Facilities and Infrastructure Act, nd (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Council of the States, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Executive Summary, Capital Outlay Projects, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Fauquier Farmers, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Federal Projects, Battle flag, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Federal Projects, Chesapeake Bay Foundation, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Federal Projects, Energy Efficiency Working Groups, 2012-2013 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Federal Projects, Fox penning, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Federal Projects, Gathright Dam, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Federal Projects, Indian Recognition, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Federal Projects, Inspector General Issues, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Federal Projects, Misc., 2013 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Federal Projects, National Ocean Policy, MARCO, 2012-2013 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Federal Projects, Offshore Wind VOWDA, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Federal Projects, Sequestration Letters, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Federal Projects, Third Track Rail Project (DGIF), 2010 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Federal Projects, Va. Higher Education Consortium for Nuclear Energy, 2012-2013 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Briefing, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Citizens for a Fort Monroe National Park, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Concept for the U.S. National Military Museum, ca. 2010 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Correspondence, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Decision Briefs, 2007-2009 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Economics, 2008-2009 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Environmental Updates, 2008-2010 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Excerpts from the Fort Monroe Historic Preservation Design Standards, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Governance Subcommittee, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Manual, Board of Directors, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Media, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Meetings, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Meetings, 2009-2010 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Meetings, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Meetings, 2011 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Meetings, 2013 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Misc., 2011 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, National Park Service, 2009-2010 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Programmatic Agreement, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Reconnaissance Study, 2008 May (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Reuse Plan, 2006-2009 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority, Reuse Plan, 2008 June (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - General Assembly, Legislation, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - General Assembly, Votes, 2013 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Governor's Commission on Economic Development and Job Creation, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Governor's Conference on Energy, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Great Falls Citizens Association, Groundwater contamination, 2013 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - The Hand Site, Historical Highway Marker (Cheroenhaka (Nottoway) Indian Tribe of Southampton County, Virginia), 2010 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Historic districts, ca. 2010 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hurricane Irene, 2011 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Land conservation, ca. 2010-2013 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Land Preservation Tax Credit Program Report, 2009-2010 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, Meeting, 2011-2012 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Virginia Land Conservation Grants, Misc., 2011-2013 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Amelia County (Sailor's Creek), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Chesapeake Bay (Land and Water Conservation Fund), 2012 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Frederick County (Boyer/Ogden's Cave), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Henry County (Mayo), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Henry County (Mayo-Thompson), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Lee County (Cope Tract) (Box 13, Folder 12a)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Lee County (Cridlin Tract), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Lee County (Mason Tract), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Loudoun County (Bane), nd (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Montgomery County (Sandy), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Northampton County (Davis Tract), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Nottoway County (Burkeville), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Orange County (Walmart), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Prince Edward County (Fowlkes Tract), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Prince Edward and Appomattox Counties (Pamplin-Norfolk Southern), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Richmond County (Fones Clift), 2013 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Roanoke County (Hafer Estate), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Russell County (Lark Tract), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Scott County, 2011 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Scott County (Jesse Tract), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Smyth County (Hungry Mother State Park), 2012 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Suffolk County (South Quay), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Sussex County (Nottoway 2), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Land Easement and Acquisition, Wythe County (Austinville), 2011 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Legislative Mandates and Directives, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - MMS Virginia Task Force, 2009-2010 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mandates, 2011 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Marine Resource Commission, Opportunities for Offshore Wind Energy, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Marine Resource Commission, Report on Audit, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 2010-2011 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Outer Continental Shelf, Governor's Coalition, Conference, 2013 May 6 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Oyster management, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Pacific Tomato Growers, Ltd., 2010-2011 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Potomac River Fisheries Commission, Meeting, 2013 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Chesapeake Bay and Virginia Waters Clean-Up Plan, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Governor's Transportation Finding and Reform Package, 2013 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Living on Karst, 2013 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Project Underground: A Natural Resource Education Guide, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Regional Fishery Management Councils, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Secretaries Energy Efficiency Working Group and VEMP2 Grant Project Kick-Off, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Tennessee Valley Authority, Erosion Monitoring, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Virginia Conservation Network, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Virginia Groundwater Availability Issues, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Virginia Soil and Water Conservation Districts Funding Study, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Review of General Fund Revenues and the Virginia Economy, 2011-2012 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Salary project, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Shenandoah National Park (Madison Co., Va.), 2013 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Sierra Club, Power Failure: How Virginia is losing the competition for clean energy, 2010 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Shoreline Management, 2003-2010 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Water Quality Monitoring Program, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Smith Mountain Pumped Storage Project, 2010 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Southern States Energy Board, 2011 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Southern States Energy Board, 2013 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - Strategic Plan, 2010-2012 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Sustaining Military Readiness Conference, 2011 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Talking points, 2010-2011 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - United Cherokee Indian Tribe of Virginia, Inc., 2007 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Uranium, 2011-2012 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Norfolk District Update, 2011 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - U.S. vs. Beazer Homes USA, Inc., 2011 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - U.S. vs. Beazer Homes USA, Inc., 2011 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - U.S. EPA, Procedural Review of EPA Greenhouse Gases, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - U.S. House Committee on Agriculture, Conservation, Energy, and Forestry Subcommittee Public Hearing, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Agreements with Other Nations, Germany, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Agreements with Other Nations, Israel, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Agreements with Other Nations, Mexico, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Agreements with Other Nations, United Kingdom, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Bar Association, Annual meeting, 2013 January (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Canopy Tours, ca. 2010-2013 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Commission on Energy and Environment, 2010 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Institute of Marine Science, Visit, 2011 April (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Invasive Species, Working Group, Meeting, 2012 August (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Land Conservation, Conference, 2010 May (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, Meetings, 2012 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Museum of Natural History, 2011 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Outdoor Foundation, 2010 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Virginia State Tribal Recognition, Nottoway Indian Tribe of Virginia, Inc., 2009 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Warren County Power Station, 2011 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Yorktown Naval Weapons Station, 2012 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Series II: Decision Memoranda and Briefs, 2010-2013., Extent: 6 boxes (2.1 cu. ft.). (Box 19-24)
  Series II: Decision Memoranda and Briefs, 2010-2013, is housed in six boxes and arranged alphabetically by folder title. This series includes correspondence, decision briefs, memorandum, requests, and other related materials. Included are decision tracking sheets with attached correspondence or memoranda detailing the topics. Also included are critical hiring requests for the Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of Environmental Quality, Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of Historic Resources, Marine Resources Commission, and the Virginia Museum of Natural History.
  - Decision Briefs, 2010-2011 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 2-5)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, Completed sub-aqueous land use, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2011 January-February (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2011 March-April (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2011 April-May (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2011 June-July (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2011 July-September (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2011 September-October (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2011 October-December (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2012 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Decision Tracking Sheets, 2013 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Agency Preparedness Assessment results, 2012 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2010 January-June (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2010 August-December (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2011 January-May (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2011 June-December (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2012 January-July (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2012 August-December (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2013 January-May (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2013 June (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2013 July-August (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Historic Resources, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Marine Resources Commission, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Virginia Museum of Natural History (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Pending, 2010-2011 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 2011 (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 2011 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Historic Resources, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Marine Resources Commission, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Virginia Museum of Natural History, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Critical Hiring Requests, Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 5)